Arthur Carson

Full Stack Software Engineer

(414) 400-3449

rthrcrsn@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/arthurcarson/

https://github.com/Real-Arthur https://www.arthurcarson.com/

LANGUAGES/TOOLS

- HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, React.js, Node.js, Express, Redux, React Native, Python, Flask, Redis, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, AWS DynamoDB, JSON, Axios, Ajax, RESTful API, CLI, Jest, Material-UI, Bootstrap
- Visual Studio Code, Postman, Postico, Github, Git, Trello, Slack, Zoom, Google Meet, Docker, Heroku

PROJECTS

Playworks Step Challenge — Group Project

Collaborated with a team of four responsible writing and design a web application to make it easier for the PlayWorks organization to arrange and manage an event such as a step challenge or a virtual home run derby

Automated the formerly time consuming aspects of organizing and maintaining a competition within a large organization and between organizations

Streamlined posted photos curation, scheduled daily challenges by date, updated contest rules and FAQ, exported contest results to CSV, and calculated leaderboards by contests and team

Technologies Used: AWS S3, PostgreSQL, Redux, Axios, React.js, Node.js, Material-UI, Javascript, CSS, HTML

Cast Watch — Solo Project

Wrote and designed an app, including technical scope document, to make it easier to look up a movie or actor/actress to find out if anyone in the movie has been in anything else the user has seen

Answers that pesky question of "What have I seen them in?" that people get when watching a movie

Built accessing a third-party database to scan the cast of a movie and to scan the filmography of an actor/actress. Comparing that data to a user built personal library to find matches of films and actors/actresses

Technologies Used: PostgreSQL, Third-party API, Postman, Redux, Axios, React.js, Node.js, Material-UI, jQuery, Javascript, CSS, HTML

EXPERIENCE

Prime Digital Academy

Full Stack Software Engineering Student

June 2020- November 2020

Accelerated, immersion full stack software engineering/software development program with highlights of diversity/inclusion education, career development, and public speaking.

To change career trajectories and teach the most practical, ubiquitous technology and techniques as well as best practices.

Lake & Irving, Minneapolis, MN

Food Server

August 2018 - July 2020

Delivered a high level of customer service to ensure consistent, excellent experiences

Cooperated with a diverse group of team members, about 10-15 people, in different departments on a day-to-day basis

Vagabond, Milwaukee, WI

Food Server/Expo

August 2015 - July 2018

Trained and mentored new servers and was an example of calm and organization in an often chaotic atmosphere

Developed an understanding of the system and organizational style of company

EDUCATION

Prime Digital Academy Minneapolis, MN

Degree: Full Stack Software Engineering

Certification

June 2020- November 2020